Table calculations are performed from the results of a view like
“表计算”(Table Calculations) 是由视图的结果驱动执行的
showing the percent of total sales that comes from a particular region.
比如显示某特定区域占销售总额百分比的视图
Let's use a table calculation to show the percent of sales that comes from each market.
我们使用表计算来显示每个市场的销售百分比
First, let's plot the sum of profit by market.
首先 我们绘制按市场划分的利润总额图
Now, by right clicking on the sum profit,
然后 右击“总利润”(Sum Profit)
you can see add table calculation.
可以看到“添加表计算”(Add Table Calculation)
You can manually set the table calculation from this window.
你可以从此窗口手动设置表计算
Or you can use the quick table calculation from the dropdown.
或者从下拉列表中使用“快速表计算”(Quick Table Calculation)
Let's add a quick table calculation to show the percent of total.
我们添加一个快速表计算来显示“占总额的百分比”(Percent of Total)
When we do so, we can quickly see that APAC represents nearly 30 percent of total sales.
这样做时 我们很快可以看到亚太地区占销售总额的近 30％
Let's try one more example.
再来看一个例子 00:00:37,850 --&gt; 00:00:40,710 我们使用表计算来显示季度销售额的增长情况
To start, let's create a line plot of sales by
首先 通过将 Sales 添加到行功能区
adding sales to the rows and order date to the columns.
将 Order Date 添加到列功能区来创建折线图
Now, let's drill down to quarters by clicking this plus sign.
现在 我们点击这个加号来深入到“季度”
You can see that this creates four different plots.
可以看到这创建了四个不同的图
This is because the order date is,
这是因为 order date
currently, a discrete variable.
当前是一个离散变量
Let's change this by right clicking on order date,
我们来进行更改 右击“订单日期”(Order Date)
selecting convert to continuous,
选择“转变为连续变量”(Convert to Continuous)
and then re-adding it to the column shelf.
然后重新将它添加到列功能区
Now, we're ready to add the table calculation.
现在 我们可以添加表计算了
Let's right click on sum of sales,
右击 “销售总额” SUM(Sales)
select quick table calculation,
选择“快速表计算”(Quick Table Calculation)
and click on percent difference.
然后点击“百分比差异”(Percent Difference)
Now, we see the percent difference from quarter to quarter.
现在我们可以看到各季度之间的百分比差异
Perhaps, we want to get even more granular with our line plot by drilling down to week.
我们还可能想要深入到“周” 来进一步细化折线图的颗粒
As you can see, the data gets pretty erratic at that level of granularity.
如你所见 数据在这样细的颗粒度级别上变得十分反复无常
We can use a table calculation to use
我们还可以使用表计算中的“移动计算”(Moving Calculation)
a moving average to make the graph more comprehensible.
（以消除短期波动）来使图表更易于理解